<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>News on </title>
    <link>https://jwcaterine.com/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 09:27:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jwcaterine.com/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>USDA Funding for Food Banks Delayed</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 09:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/snap/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s still unclear why over $6 million in USDA funding for VA farmers and food banks took so long to be released. This was one of those stories that was developing as I was covering it which is always exciting if a little nerve-wracking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retired Poquoson Fire Chief Bio</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/poqfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 15:07:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/poqfire/</guid>
      <description>I did an interview with retired Poquoson Fire Chief Robert Holloway. Growing up in Poquoson, it&amp;rsquo;s a milestone for me to do a story about the place where I lived for so many years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WJCC School Board Coverage</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/schoolboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 18:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/schoolboard/</guid>
      <description>I covered the school board in Austin for the Monitor, and now I&amp;rsquo;m covering the WJCC school board. The main points of comment at the latest meeting were the book removal at a couple of local high schools as well as the nontransportation zones which are expected to apply to elementary schools in the coming school year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Tours at Jamestown</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/hjtours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 18:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/hjtours/</guid>
      <description>I covered the new tours at Historic Jamestown. It is quickly becoming one of my favorite places to visit locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Glide Profile</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/xglide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 15:07:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/xglide/</guid>
      <description>I published my first piece in RVA Mag about young dancer X-Glide. As a dancer myself, I was grateful for the opportunity to give back to the Virginia dance scene as well as show off my photography more than my usual pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James City County Budget</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/jcc_coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 18:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/jcc_coverage/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be covering more James City County Board Meetings and continuing to learn more about local politics. I also covered the following WJCC school board meeting where the division approved their budget as well, including a 7% raise for teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidewalk Project</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/sidewalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 16:26:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/sidewalk/</guid>
      <description>I covered a sidewalk project that has been several years in the making near Clara Byrd Baker Elementary School. I had been trying to get hold of the school&amp;rsquo;s principal for an interview without any luck, but when I went to the site to take photos I ended up running into him! Journalism 101.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term Rentals</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/str/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 09:13:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/str/</guid>
      <description>I felt like I was back in Austin doing my housing beat when I attended the JCC Planning Commission Meeting this past week.
If city commission meetings were D&amp;amp;D games does that make staff the DM?
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) May 3, 2023  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedal the Parkway</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/bicycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 09:13:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/bicycling/</guid>
      <description>I did a preview piece on Pedal the Parkway which is happening this weekend. Can&amp;rsquo;t speak for my readers but I know my wife and I were hesitant to go on the chance we could be charged the entrance fee. I also posted a video with Emil from the Bicycle Co-Op explaining how he fixes up old bikes:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Williamsburg Landing Arboretum</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/arboretum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 09:13:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/arboretum/</guid>
      <description>I attended the Williamsburg Landing Arboretum Arbor Day celebration a week ago. One of the great things about reporting is learning new vocabulary like &amp;ldquo;cultivar,&amp;rdquo; a plant variety produced by selective breeding. I also posted a video of Grounds lead Justin Drewery explaining how to properly plant a potted tree:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Your Arts Dance Event</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/studyyourarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:07:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/studyyourarts/</guid>
      <description>X-Glide, winner of the Study Your Arts event
I competed and reported on the Study Your Arts dance competition at this year&amp;rsquo;s Something in the Water festival in VA Beach. It was a blast to return to the dance scene where my artistic journey began and be able to give back by covering the event as a journalist. So much talent among the young dancers - I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what happens next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic Jamestowne Volunteers</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/jamestown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 15:23:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/jamestown/</guid>
      <description>I had the chance to go behind the scenes at Historic Jamestowne and meet some of the volunteers who work in the conservation lab as well as interpreters at the fort site. As a teenager visiting Historic Jamestowne, I mostly remember the heat. Now as an adult who actually appreciates history, I found everything there fascinating. It is very much an active archaeological site with new digs happening all the time, and I plan to go back soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lawrenceville Correctional Center</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/lvcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 15:23:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/lvcc/</guid>
      <description>I published my first article in the Virginia Mercury on the only privately run prison in Virginia, Lawrenceville Correctional Center. I obtained a series of memos from the Virginia Department of Corrections that showed GEO Group, the private operator, has had $4.3 million in contract breaches since 2018. I uploaded the memos to DocumentCloud along with the contract and other related documents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
