<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 15:33:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>July Photography</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/julypics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 15:33:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/julypics/</guid>
      <description>After I moved back to Virginia, I had the opportunity to start taking pictures as part of my reporting for the Gazette. Starting in July, I&amp;rsquo;ve made more of an effort to practice the craft and learn about photography. Here are some of the shots I took in my spare time around the Williamsburg area.
Norge pic.twitter.com/IF3lLkapO2
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) July 22, 2023  I got that D.O.G. (Street) in me pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virginia Business August Issue</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/vbaugust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 15:33:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/vbaugust/</guid>
      <description>I have four stories in the August Issue of Virginia Business: one on Richmond&amp;rsquo;s repeal of minimum parking requirements, one on a couple of Virginia startup incubators competing for a SBA grant, one on a new tuition-assistance program at MBU, and one about the city of Bristol&amp;rsquo;s switch to a new destination marketing organization in Southwest Virginia.
This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve published my work in a magazine - happy to put another notch on my journalism belt!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCC Terminates School Contract</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/schoolsplit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/schoolsplit/</guid>
      <description>I spoke with a few different sources after James City County announced it would end its contract with the school division, and people were in shock. I will be covering the school board work session tomorrow, where the superintendent is expected to speak publicly for the first time on it. Will be interesting to see how this issue develops into the fall, when the City of Williamsburg plans to start its feasibility study on starting its own school division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalism 101</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/journalism101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 10:58:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/journalism101/</guid>
      <description>This week I posted a quick tutorial on Reddit about how to cover a local government meeting if you want to start a career in journalism:
   &amp;ldquo;Howdy! For those of you who still want to get into journalism despite the many warnings about why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, I wanted to share some advice on how to start as a freelance journalist even if you have no experience. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in the US news industry since 2016, and I never went to school for journalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction on Richmond Rd</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/richmondrd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 10:55:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/richmondrd/</guid>
      <description>Better sidewalks and new bike lanes are coming to the area around the Norge Shopping Center. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Norge in a minute. It was nice to visit and take some pictures.
Norge pic.twitter.com/IF3lLkapO2
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) July 22, 2023  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WJCC New Library Rule</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/newbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 20:15:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/newbook/</guid>
      <description>The new policy takes away parents&amp;rsquo; abilities to remove books for all children at a school like what happened earlier this year. It followed a memo by the state superintendent, but I&amp;rsquo;m curious if other localities will interpret it in the same way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastern State Property Sale</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/easternstate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 08:57:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/easternstate/</guid>
      <description>Fun fact - I actually ran a cross-country meet in high school on the Eastern State Hospital campus. Now over 300 acres of that property is for sale, although the finalized timeline of when a deal will close is still up in the air. These parcels were determined to be in excess of what the hospital needed, although my other recent report on the shortage of state beds for psychiatric patients brings that assessment into question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grove</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/grove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 08:57:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/grove/</guid>
      <description>Grove is a beautiful neighborhood in south James City County with a rich history that unfortunately hasn&amp;rsquo;t always gotten the attention it deserves. While reporting for this story I had the chance to volunteer at the Grove rec center for a beginning of summer festival, and it was a pleasure getting to meet the residents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Coding Video Walkthrough</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/loc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 13:14:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/loc/</guid>
      <description>Today I published a story for Virginia Mercury about failures of the state&amp;rsquo;s psychiatric system, specifically not having enough beds to accomodate those in mental health crisis. I recorded a video walkthrough on how I was able to write some simple code in Python to extract, analyze, and visualize the data from a public records request that became the basis of this story.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Parkway Rehabilitation</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/colrehab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 10:01:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/colrehab/</guid>
      <description>It will be interesting to see how the entrance fee controversy with Colonial Parkway earlier this year plays out in the context of this bigger rehabilitation project as far as the community&amp;rsquo;s relationship with the National Park Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driver&#39;s Ed Equity</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/driversed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 10:00:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/driversed/</guid>
      <description>I want to look at equity issues at WJCC schools beyond this story on driver&amp;rsquo;s education not being offered at Lafayette High School with the highest minority student population, but content to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juneteenth</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/juneteenth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 10:00:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/juneteenth/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s Juneteenth celebration in Williamsburg was super fun and educational. I hope next year it will be a bigger countywide event.
Some more moments from #Juneteenth celebration in #Williamsburg https://t.co/jSik50xydD pic.twitter.com/pfUkSEKcGR
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) June 20, 2023  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIMS Science Day</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/vims/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 09:52:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/vims/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I were visiting the Virginia Institute of Marine Science for their annual Science Day open house, and I realized I should probably write a story about it! It&amp;rsquo;s amazing all of the cool places I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of when I went to school in the area a decade ago. Definitely plan on going back!
     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term Rental Twist</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/strfinal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 09:51:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/strfinal/</guid>
      <description>The Board of Supervisors approved a couple of Special Use Permits against the recommendation of the planning commission this past week. These are the first cases I&amp;rsquo;ve reported on from start to finish since I started doing journalism in Virginia. You can read my planning commission coverage here and the discussion at this month&amp;rsquo;s joint meeting to get the full story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCC to Join York Emergency Center</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/ems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 07:12:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/ems/</guid>
      <description>Published a story this week on the pending merger of the local emergency call center to now include James City County.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Coming to WJCC Schools</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/solar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 07:12:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/solar/</guid>
      <description>This week I reported on Dominion Energy Solutions pitching solar roofs to WJCC schools. It brings me back to when I reported on solar power in Austin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term Rentals and Libraries</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/strsandlibrary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 07:33:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/strsandlibrary/</guid>
      <description>This week I had a few pieces come out in the Gazette, including my coverage of the JCC Board of Supervisors meeting. Two of the main topics of discussion were possible new regulations for short-term rentals as well as plans for new libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USDA Funding for Food Banks Delayed</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 09:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/snap/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s still unclear why over $6 million in USDA funding for VA farmers and food banks took so long to be released. This was one of those stories that was developing as I was covering it which is always exciting if a little nerve-wracking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retired Poquoson Fire Chief Bio</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/poqfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 15:07:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/poqfire/</guid>
      <description>I did an interview with retired Poquoson Fire Chief Robert Holloway. Growing up in Poquoson, it&amp;rsquo;s a milestone for me to do a story about the place where I lived for so many years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WJCC School Board Coverage</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/schoolboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 18:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/schoolboard/</guid>
      <description>I covered the school board in Austin for the Monitor, and now I&amp;rsquo;m covering the WJCC school board. The main points of comment at the latest meeting were the book removal at a couple of local high schools as well as the nontransportation zones which are expected to apply to elementary schools in the coming school year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Tours at Jamestown</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/hjtours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 18:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/hjtours/</guid>
      <description>I covered the new tours at Historic Jamestown. It is quickly becoming one of my favorite places to visit locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Glide Profile</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/xglide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 15:07:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/xglide/</guid>
      <description>I published my first piece in RVA Mag about young dancer X-Glide. As a dancer myself, I was grateful for the opportunity to give back to the Virginia dance scene as well as show off my photography more than my usual pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James City County Budget</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/jcc_coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 18:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/jcc_coverage/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be covering more James City County Board Meetings and continuing to learn more about local politics. I also covered the following WJCC school board meeting where the division approved their budget as well, including a 7% raise for teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidewalk Project</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/sidewalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 16:26:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/sidewalk/</guid>
      <description>I covered a sidewalk project that has been several years in the making near Clara Byrd Baker Elementary School. I had been trying to get hold of the school&amp;rsquo;s principal for an interview without any luck, but when I went to the site to take photos I ended up running into him! Journalism 101.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term Rentals</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/str/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 09:13:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/str/</guid>
      <description>I felt like I was back in Austin doing my housing beat when I attended the JCC Planning Commission Meeting this past week.
If city commission meetings were D&amp;amp;D games does that make staff the DM?
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) May 3, 2023  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedal the Parkway</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/bicycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 09:13:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/bicycling/</guid>
      <description>I did a preview piece on Pedal the Parkway which is happening this weekend. Can&amp;rsquo;t speak for my readers but I know my wife and I were hesitant to go on the chance we could be charged the entrance fee. I also posted a video with Emil from the Bicycle Co-Op explaining how he fixes up old bikes:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Your Arts Dance Event</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/studyyourarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:07:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/studyyourarts/</guid>
      <description>X-Glide, winner of the Study Your Arts event
I competed and reported on the Study Your Arts dance competition at this year&amp;rsquo;s Something in the Water festival in VA Beach. It was a blast to return to the dance scene where my artistic journey began and be able to give back by covering the event as a journalist. So much talent among the young dancers - I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what happens next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic Jamestowne Volunteers</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/jamestown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 15:23:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/jamestown/</guid>
      <description>I had the chance to go behind the scenes at Historic Jamestowne and meet some of the volunteers who work in the conservation lab as well as interpreters at the fort site. As a teenager visiting Historic Jamestowne, I mostly remember the heat. Now as an adult who actually appreciates history, I found everything there fascinating. It is very much an active archaeological site with new digs happening all the time, and I plan to go back soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lawrenceville Correctional Center</title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/lvcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 15:23:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/lvcc/</guid>
      <description>I published my first article in the Virginia Mercury on the only privately run prison in Virginia, Lawrenceville Correctional Center. I obtained a series of memos from the Virginia Department of Corrections that showed GEO Group, the private operator, has had $4.3 million in contract breaches since 2018. I uploaded the memos to DocumentCloud along with the contract and other related documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/arboretum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gam32bit.github.io/jwcat757/posts/arboretum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
