<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>James City County on </title>
    <link>https://jwcaterine.com/tags/james-city-county/</link>
    <description>Recent content in James City County on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 15:33:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jwcaterine.com/tags/james-city-county/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>July Photography</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/julypics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 15:33:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/julypics/</guid>
      <description>After I moved back to Virginia, I had the opportunity to start taking pictures as part of my reporting for the Gazette. Starting in July, I&amp;rsquo;ve made more of an effort to practice the craft and learn about photography. Here are some of the shots I took in my spare time around the Williamsburg area.
Norge pic.twitter.com/IF3lLkapO2
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) July 22, 2023  I got that D.O.G. (Street) in me pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCC Terminates School Contract</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/schoolsplit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/schoolsplit/</guid>
      <description>I spoke with a few different sources after James City County announced it would end its contract with the school division, and people were in shock. I will be covering the school board work session tomorrow, where the superintendent is expected to speak publicly for the first time on it. Will be interesting to see how this issue develops into the fall, when the City of Williamsburg plans to start its feasibility study on starting its own school division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction on Richmond Rd</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/richmondrd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 10:55:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/richmondrd/</guid>
      <description>Better sidewalks and new bike lanes are coming to the area around the Norge Shopping Center. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Norge in a minute. It was nice to visit and take some pictures.
Norge pic.twitter.com/IF3lLkapO2
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) July 22, 2023  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grove</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/grove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 08:57:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/grove/</guid>
      <description>Grove is a beautiful neighborhood in south James City County with a rich history that unfortunately hasn&amp;rsquo;t always gotten the attention it deserves. While reporting for this story I had the chance to volunteer at the Grove rec center for a beginning of summer festival, and it was a pleasure getting to meet the residents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Parkway Rehabilitation</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/colrehab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 10:01:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/colrehab/</guid>
      <description>It will be interesting to see how the entrance fee controversy with Colonial Parkway earlier this year plays out in the context of this bigger rehabilitation project as far as the community&amp;rsquo;s relationship with the National Park Service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
