<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Williamsburg on </title>
    <link>https://jwcaterine.com/tags/williamsburg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Williamsburg on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 16:26:20 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jwcaterine.com/tags/williamsburg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sidewalk</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/sidewalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 16:26:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/sidewalk/</guid>
      <description>I covered a sidewalk project that has been several years in the making near Clara Byrd Baker Elementary School. I had been trying to get hold of the school&amp;rsquo;s principal for an interview without any luck, but when I went to the site to take photos I ended up running into him! Journalism 101.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term Rentals</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/str/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 09:13:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/str/</guid>
      <description>I felt like I was back in Austin doing my housing beat when I attended the JCC Planning Commission Meeting this past week.
If city commission meetings were D&amp;amp;D games does that make staff the DM?
&amp;mdash; JW Caterine (@jwcat757) May 3, 2023  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedal the Parkway</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/bicycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 09:13:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/bicycling/</guid>
      <description>I did a preview piece on Pedal the Parkway which is happening this weekend. Can&amp;rsquo;t speak for my readers but I know my wife and I were hesitant to go on the chance we could be charged the entrance fee. I also posted a video with Emil from the Bicycle Co-Op explaining how he fixes up old bikes:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Williamsburg Landing Arboretum</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/arboretum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 09:13:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/arboretum/</guid>
      <description>I attended the Williamsburg Landing Arboretum Arbor Day celebration a week ago. One of the great things about reporting is learning new vocabulary like &amp;ldquo;cultivar,&amp;rdquo; a plant variety produced by selective breeding. I also posted a video of Grounds lead Justin Drewery explaining how to properly plant a potted tree:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic Jamestowne Volunteers</title>
      <link>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/jamestown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 15:23:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwcaterine.com/posts/jamestown/</guid>
      <description>I had the chance to go behind the scenes at Historic Jamestowne and meet some of the volunteers who work in the conservation lab as well as interpreters at the fort site. As a teenager visiting Historic Jamestowne, I mostly remember the heat. Now as an adult who actually appreciates history, I found everything there fascinating. It is very much an active archaeological site with new digs happening all the time, and I plan to go back soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
